Bernard C. Smith Papers
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
Bernard C. Smith Papers 1963-1969
nam_apap279
10.4 cubic ft.
Smith, Bernard C.
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
The Bernard C. Smith Papers document the first four years of Smith’s service as a New York State Senator. While Smith is most well known for his work in conservation, these papers from his early Senate career contain significant materials on the issues of abortion, education (especially for mentally handicapped children), medical treatment and penal codes and laws.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Bernard C. Smith initially donated his papers to Syracuse University in 1969. In 2006, the papers were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Biographical Sketch
Bernard C. Smith was born in Barnesboro, Pennsylvania in 1923. World War II interrupted his studies at Cornell University and during the war he served as a lieutenant and platoon commander of a tank battalion in the Pacific Theatre. When Smith returned home he continued his studies at Cornell where he majored in government and law. He subsequently earned his bachelor of arts degree and a law degree. He practiced law for 44 years, in both private practice and the public sector. From 1951-1958 he served as a New York State Assistant District Attorney, obtaining the title of Chief Assistant by 1958. He served as District Attorney of Suffolk County from 1962-1965.
In 1965 voters of the 2nd District (part of Suffolk County), elected Smith, a Republican, to represent them in the New York State Senate. During his early years as a State Senator Smith focused on the debate surrounding the question of whether or not to legalize abortion in New York, on creating legislation that would help provide better educational services for mentally handicapped students, and for revising and updating penal codes and laws in an attempt to deal with crime in the state. Smith also began to introduce legislation to protect the environment, which became the main focus of his work in later years.
By the end of his Senate career in 1978, Smith had chaired the Conservation Committee and helped to found the Adirondack Park Agency and the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation. From 1978-1990 Smith served as the commissioner of the State Investigation Committee.
Smith was married to the former Elizabeth Reynolds for 44 years and they had five children. In 1993 at the age of 70, Smith passed away from an inoperable brain tumor.
This collection contains papers from Bernard C. Smith’s early career as a State Senator, from 1965-1969. In Series 1, Subject Files, the topics with the largest amount of information are abortion, education (especially special education), medical treatment and penal codes. The abortion files contain a significant number of opinions of New York citizens (in the form of correspondence and formal testimony) at the time New York’s abortion laws were being reconsidered. The education files include materials on debates surrounding busing to questions about decentralization and funding. Materials pertaining to medical treatment range from provision of Medicaid to improvement of New York State's mental health resources. The files on penal codes contain information about penal laws and institutions, and there are other related subject files on issues of crime in general.
The Smith Papers contain an abundant amount of Smith’s correspondence with his constituents. Researchers who are interested in studying public opinion on issues of abortion, education, medicine, penal law, and environmental protection in the late 1960s will find ample materials in this collection.
While there are materials in Series 1 that relate to environmental conservation, there are no materials that directly pertain to the creation of the Adirondack Park Agency or the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation, which were developed after 1969. There are, however, individual subject files that pertain to certain specific conservation issues such as the Conservation Bill of Rights and regulation of game fishing.
Series 2, Bills, contains files pertaining to each of the bills that Smith introduced in the State Senate in 1968.
Please note that there also are background materials in Series 1 which Smith referenced while a State Senator that date to 1963-1964.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - Subject Files, 1963-1969, Undated
Series 2 - Bills, 1967-1968
Series 1 is arranged alphabetically and Series 2 is arranged chronologically by bill number.
Subject and Genre Headings
Politics and Politicians; Smith, Bernard C.; New York (State). Legislature. Senate; New York (State). Legislature. Senate. Committe on Penal Institutions; New York (State). Legislature. Senate. Committee on Environmental Conservation and Recreation; New York (State). Legislature. Senate. Standing Committee on Insurance; New York (State). Legislature. Senate. Committee on Finance; New York (State). Legislature. Senate. Education Committee; New York (State). Legislature. Senate. Standing Committee on Codes; New York (State). Legislature. Senate. Standing Committee on Banks; Abortion--New York (State); Abortion--New York (State)--Public opinion; Conservation of natural resources--New York (State); Education--New York (State); Special education--Law and legislation--New York (State); Special education--New York (State); Mental health--New York (State); Mental retardation--New York (State); Medicaid--New York (State); Criminal law---New York (State); New York (State)--Politics and government; Bills (legislative records); Clippings; Correspondence; Files by subject; Legislative records; Photographs; Official reports
Container List
- Subject Files, 1963-1969; Undated; nam_apap279-1; 9.75 cu. ft.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Series 1, Subject Files, consists of the files Smith maintained between the years of 1965-1969.
  - "A New State Park Concept…Caumsett" (Publication), Undated; nam_apap279-1_1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abortion, 1967; nam_apap279-1_2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Abortion, 1968; nam_apap279-1_3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Abortion Law, 1967; nam_apap279-1_4 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - Abortion Law, 1968; nam_apap279-1_5 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Abortion Law Publications, 1966-1968; Undated; nam_apap279-1_6 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Abortion Law - Reports and Testimony, 1966-1967; nam_apap279-1_7 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Abortion Law - Reports and Testimony, 1967; nam_apap279-1_8 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Abortion Legislation, 1969; nam_apap279-1_9 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - Accountants Association, 1968; nam_apap279-1_10 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Action, 1969; nam_apap279-1_11 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Adoption Proceedings, 1966; 1968; nam_apap279-1_12 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Advertising, 1969; nam_apap279-1_13 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Advisory Committee on Intergovernmental Relations, 1968; nam_apap279-1_14 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Agriculture, 1968; nam_apap279-1_15 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Air Pollution, 1968; nam_apap279-1_16 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Air Pollution, 1969; nam_apap279-1_17 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Alcoholic Beverage Commission, 1965-1966; nam_apap279-1_18 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - American Legion, 1969; nam_apap279-1_19 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Anti-Poverty Bill, 1967; nam_apap279-1_20 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Architects, 1969; nam_apap279-1_21 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Atomic and Space Development Authority, 1968; nam_apap279-1_22 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Atomic Power, 1969; nam_apap279-1_23 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Attorney General, 1969; nam_apap279-1_24 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Auto Mechanics, 1968; nam_apap279-1_25 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Automobiles, 1968; nam_apap279-1_26 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Automobile Club, 1969; nam_apap279-1_27 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Automotive Shop Licensing Hearing, 1968; nam_apap279-1_28 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Banks Committee, 1968; nam_apap279-1_29 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Banking, 1967; Undated; nam_apap279-1_30 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Bayville-Rye Bridge Project, 1966; nam_apap279-1_31 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Belleayre Ski Area, 1969; nam_apap279-1_32 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bills, 1969; nam_apap279-1_33 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Bills for Study, 1968; nam_apap279-1_34 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Blaine Amendment, 1968; nam_apap279-1_35 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Blind, Undated; nam_apap279-1_36 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - BOCES, 1969; nam_apap279-1_37 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Brain Injured, 1967; nam_apap279-1_38 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Brentwood Public School District, 1969; nam_apap279-1_39 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Bridge Construction, 1967; nam_apap279-1_40 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Bridge Program, 1969; nam_apap279-1_41 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Brooklyn Polytechnic, 1969; nam_apap279-1_42 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Budget, 1969; nam_apap279-1_43 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Budget Message of Governor, 1969; nam_apap279-1_44 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bureau of Attendance, 1968; nam_apap279-1_45 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Busing, 1969; nam_apap279-1_46 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Campaign Guidelines, 1966; nam_apap279-1_47 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Canners and Freezers Association, Inc., 1968; nam_apap279-1_48 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Capital Punishment, 1968; nam_apap279-1_49 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Central School District #5, 1968; nam_apap279-1_50 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Centerport-Mill Pond, 1966; nam_apap279-1_51 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Chiropractic Practice, 1969; nam_apap279-1_52 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Church, 1968; nam_apap279-1_53 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - City of New York, Undated; nam_apap279-1_54 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Civil Practice Law, 1969; nam_apap279-1_55 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Civil Rights, 1965-1966; 1968; nam_apap279-1_56 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Civil Service, 1968; nam_apap279-1_57 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Civil Service - Correspondence, 1968; nam_apap279-1_58 (Box 2, Folder 17 -18)
  - Civil Service Employees Association, 1967; nam_apap279-1_59 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Civil Service Law, 1969; nam_apap279-1_60 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Civil Service - Memos and Reports, 1966-1968; nam_apap279-1_61 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Clinical Laboratories, 1966; nam_apap279-1_62 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Codes, 1969; nam_apap279-1_63 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Codes - Correspondence File, 1968; nam_apap279-1_64 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Codes - General Information, 1966-1967; nam_apap279-1_65 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Codes - General Information, 1968; nam_apap279-1_66 (Box 2, Folder 26-27)
  - Commack Library, 1969; nam_apap279-1_67 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Committee on Health, 1966-1968; nam_apap279-1_68 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Compulsory Health Insurance, 1968; nam_apap279-1_69 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Compulsory Health Insurance, 1969; nam_apap279-1_70 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Condemnation Procedures, 1969; nam_apap279-1_71 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Condon-Waldin Law, 1966-1967; nam_apap279-1_72 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Congratulatory Letters, 1968; nam_apap279-1_73 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Congratulatory Letters, 1969; nam_apap279-1_74 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Contractors, 1968; nam_apap279-1_75 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Conservation - Bill of Rights, 1969; nam_apap279-1_76 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Conservation - Snow Mobile, 1969; nam_apap279-1_77 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Conservative Party, 1969; nam_apap279-1_78 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Constitutional Convention, 1965-1967; nam_apap279-1_79 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Constitutional Reform, 1968; nam_apap279-1_80 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Construction and Contractors, 1968; nam_apap279-1_81 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Construction and Contractors, 1969; nam_apap279-1_82 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Consumer Problems, 1968; nam_apap279-1_83 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Consumer Protection Bill, 1969; nam_apap279-1_84 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Corporations, 1967-1968; nam_apap279-1_85 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Corporation Laws, 1969; nam_apap279-1_86 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - County Law, 1968; nam_apap279-1_87 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Crime, 1968; nam_apap279-1_88 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Criminal Law, 1969; nam_apap279-1_89 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Courts, 1968; nam_apap279-1_90 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Courts, 1969; nam_apap279-1_91 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Decentralization - Schools, 1968; nam_apap279-1_92 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Deer Hunting, 1969; nam_apap279-1_93 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Density-Sparcity Legislation, 1968; nam_apap279-1_94 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Dental Society, 1968; nam_apap279-1_95 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Disability, 1967-1968; nam_apap279-1_96 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Disclosure Bill, 1968; nam_apap279-1_97 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - District Attorney Bill, 1966-1967; nam_apap279-1_98 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Divorce Law Revision, 1965-1966; nam_apap279-1_99 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Division for Youth, 1969; nam_apap279-1_100 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Door to Door Salesmen, 1968; nam_apap279-1_101 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Drunken Driving, 1969; nam_apap279-1_102 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Drugs, 1969; nam_apap279-1_103 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Education, 1967-1968; nam_apap279-1_104 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Education, 1968; nam_apap279-1_105 (Box 3, Folder 18 - 24)
  - Education Bills, 1968; nam_apap279-1_106 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Educational Conference Board Bill, 1968; nam_apap279-1_107 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Educational Conference Board Bill, 1969; nam_apap279-1_108 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Education Reports, 1968; Undated; nam_apap279-1_109 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Education - Sex, 1969; nam_apap279-1_110 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Education - State Aid To, 1969; nam_apap279-1_111 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Engineering Legislation, 1969; nam_apap279-1_112 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Eye Treatment Center, 1967; nam_apap279-1_113 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Falconry Bill, 1969; nam_apap279-1_114 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - False and Scurrilous Campaign Literature, 1966; nam_apap279-1_115 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Family Court Act, 1968; nam_apap279-1_116 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Fiduciary Committee, 1969; nam_apap279-1_117 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Firearms, 1968; nam_apap279-1_118 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Firearms - Reports, 1968; nam_apap279-1_119 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Fire Island, 1969; nam_apap279-1_120 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Finance, 1968; nam_apap279-1_121 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Finance, 1969; nam_apap279-1_122 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Fluoridation Bill, 1969; nam_apap279-1_123 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Form Letters, 1969; nam_apap279-1_124 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Funeral Directors, 1968; nam_apap279-1_125 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Gas Bills, 1968; nam_apap279-1_126 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - General Business Laws, 1968; nam_apap279-1_127 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, 1968; nam_apap279-1_128 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, 1968-1969; nam_apap279-1_129 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - General Practitioner Bill, 1969; nam_apap279-1_130 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Gooley Dam, 1969; nam_apap279-1_131 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Government, 1969; nam_apap279-1_132 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Governor's Message, 1968; nam_apap279-1_133 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Governor's Messages - Approval/Veto, 1968; nam_apap279-1_134 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Grand Juries, 1969; nam_apap279-1_135 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Grange, 1967; nam_apap279-1_136 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Gun Control Legislation, 1969; nam_apap279-1_137 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Health, 1967; nam_apap279-1_138 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Health, 1969; nam_apap279-1_139 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Health Exam Program, 1968; nam_apap279-1_140 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Hearing Bill, 1968; nam_apap279-1_141 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Hearing Bill, 1969; nam_apap279-1_142 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Highways, 1965-1968; nam_apap279-1_143 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Highways, 1968; nam_apap279-1_144 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Highways, 1969; nam_apap279-1_145 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Highway Route 25A, 1966-1967; nam_apap279-1_146 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - "HI-SPOTS from Capitol Hill" Associated Industries of New York, 1968; nam_apap279-1_147 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Home Inspection Sales, 1968; nam_apap279-1_148 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Home Rule Messages, 1967-1968; nam_apap279-1_149 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Hospitals, 1969; nam_apap279-1_150 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Horse Trails, 1969; nam_apap279-1_151 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Home Solicitation Bill, 1969; nam_apap279-1_152 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Housing and Urban Development, 1968; nam_apap279-1_153 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission, 1968-1969; nam_apap279-1_154 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Humane Slaughter, 1967-1968; nam_apap279-1_155 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Huntington Performing Arts Foundation, 1968; nam_apap279-1_156 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Huntington Township, 1969; nam_apap279-1_157 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Hypnosis, 1966; Undated; nam_apap279-1_158 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Inspection Fees, 1968; nam_apap279-1_159 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Insurance, 1968-1969; nam_apap279-1_160 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Insurance Committee, 1968; nam_apap279-1_161 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Insurance Plan, 1966-1968; nam_apap279-1_162 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Interior Designers, 1968; nam_apap279-1_163 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - International Longshoremen's Association, 1968; nam_apap279-1_164 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Invitations, 1968; nam_apap279-1_165 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Invitations, 1969; nam_apap279-1_166 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Invitations - Current and Future, 1969; nam_apap279-1_167 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Interest, 1969; nam_apap279-1_168 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Jet Airport at Calverton, 1967-1968; nam_apap279-1_169 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Judges, 1969; nam_apap279-1_170 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Judiciary, 1969; nam_apap279-1_171 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Judiciary Law, 1967; nam_apap279-1_172 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Jurors, 1969; nam_apap279-1_173 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Justice Court Records, 1966-1967; nam_apap279-1_174 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Juvenile Crime, Undated; nam_apap279-1_175 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - "Kit Goes to the Dentist" (Requests), 1968; nam_apap279-1_176 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - La Guardia Airport, 1968; nam_apap279-1_177 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Labor, 1966-1967; nam_apap279-1_178 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Labor, 1969; nam_apap279-1_179 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Landscape Design, 1969; nam_apap279-1_180 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - League of Women Voters, 1968; nam_apap279-1_181 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Legislators' Retirement Bill, 1968; nam_apap279-1_182 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Legislative Suggestion, 1968; nam_apap279-1_183 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Letters of Recommendation, 1968; nam_apap279-1_184 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Letters of Recommendation, 1969; nam_apap279-1_185 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Liberal Party, 1966; nam_apap279-1_186 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Liberal Party, 1969; nam_apap279-1_187 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Library Districts, 1966; nam_apap279-1_188 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Licenses, 1969; nam_apap279-1_189 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Liquor, 1968; nam_apap279-1_190 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Liquor Dealers, 1969; nam_apap279-1_191 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Lotteries, 1967; nam_apap279-1_192 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Luther Johnson, 1969; nam_apap279-1_193 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Long Island, 1966; 1968; nam_apap279-1_194 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Long Island Lighting Company Employees, 1968; nam_apap279-1_195 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Long Island Railroad, 1969; nam_apap279-1_196 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Malicious Telephone Calls, 1968; nam_apap279-1_197 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Malpractice, 1968; nam_apap279-1_198 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Marriage Counselors, 1968; nam_apap279-1_199 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Mass Transportation, 1968; nam_apap279-1_200 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Mass Transportation, 1969; nam_apap279-1_201 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Mass Transportation Authority, 1967-1968; nam_apap279-1_202 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Mass Transportation - Reports and Publications, 1967-1968; nam_apap279-1_203 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Matrimony File, 1968; nam_apap279-1_204 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Meat Inspection Bill, 1968; nam_apap279-1_205 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Medcalf-Hatch Act, 1969; nam_apap279-1_206 (Box 5, Folder 27-28)
  - Medicaid, 1967-1968; nam_apap279-1_207 (Box 5, Folder 29-30)
  - Medicaid, 1968; nam_apap279-1_208 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Medicaid, 1969; nam_apap279-1_209 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Medicine, 1969; nam_apap279-1_210 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Mental Health, 1965-1968; nam_apap279-1_211 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Mental Health, 1969; nam_apap279-1_212 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Mental Retardation, 1966-1968; nam_apap279-1_213 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Mental Retardation, 1968; nam_apap279-1_214 (Box 5, Folder 37-38)
  - Mentally Retarded - Suffolk Schools, 1968; nam_apap279-1_215 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Metropolitan Transportation Authority, 1969; nam_apap279-1_216 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Migrant Labor, 1968; nam_apap279-1_217 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Migrant Labor File, 1968-1969; nam_apap279-1_218 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Minimum Salary, 1968; nam_apap279-1_219 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Model Rocketry, 1969; nam_apap279-1_220 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Mortgages, 1968; nam_apap279-1_221 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Motor Vehicle, 1965-1966; 1968; nam_apap279-1_222 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Motor Vehicles and Traffic and Highway Safety, 1968; nam_apap279-1_223 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Mourning Doves, 1969; nam_apap279-1_224 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - MTA Transportation, 1967-1968; nam_apap279-1_225 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Narcotics, 1966; nam_apap279-1_226 (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
  - Narcotics, 1969; nam_apap279-1_227 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Narcotics Rehabilitation, 1968; nam_apap279-1_228 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Narcotics Training: Working Notes and Bills as Introduced, 1967-1968; nam_apap279-1_229 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Nassau County Water Authority, 1969; nam_apap279-1_230 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Nassau County Water Bill, 1967; nam_apap279-1_231 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - National Council on Crime and Delinquency, 1966; Undated; nam_apap279-1_232 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Navigation Law, 1968; nam_apap279-1_233 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - New York City School Decentralization - Correspondence, 1969; nam_apap279-1_234 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - New York City School Decentralization - Reports, 1969; nam_apap279-1_235 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - New York Racing Association, Inc., 1966-1967; nam_apap279-1_236 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - New York State Lottery, 1969; nam_apap279-1_237 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - New York Telephone, 1968; nam_apap279-1_238 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Nuclear Power Plant, 1969; nam_apap279-1_239 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Nurserymen Land Surveyor, 1968; nam_apap279-1_240 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Nursing, 1969; nam_apap279-1_241 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Nursing Homes, 1968; nam_apap279-1_242 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Nursing Homes, 1969; nam_apap279-1_243 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Nursing Profession, 1968; nam_apap279-1_244 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Omnibus Teacher Bill, 1969; nam_apap279-1_245 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - One Year Residency Bill, 1969; nam_apap279-1_246 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Operational Grant - Title III, 1968; nam_apap279-1_247 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Optometric, 1968; nam_apap279-1_248 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Outdoor Advertising Bill, 1969; nam_apap279-1_249 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Optometry, 1969; nam_apap279-1_250 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Orthopedists, 1968; nam_apap279-1_251 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Parental Responsibility Bill, 1965-1966; nam_apap279-1_252 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Parental Responsibility Bill, 1969; nam_apap279-1_253 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Peace Officer Status, 1969; nam_apap279-1_254 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Penal Institutions - Bills Submitted, 1967; nam_apap279-1_255 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Penal Institutions - General Information, 1967; Undated; nam_apap279-1_256 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Penal Law, 1965-1966; nam_apap279-1_257 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Penal Law, 1968; nam_apap279-1_258 (Box 6, Folder 38-39)
  - Penal Law, 1969; nam_apap279-1_259 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Penal Law - Law Revision, 1967-1968; nam_apap279-1_260 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Pensions, 1969; nam_apap279-1_261 (Box 6, Folder 42)